（下村泉(しもむらいずみ)）
母さん…
Mom-
I’ll do it all over again.
私 やり直してみせるから
This time...
今度は最後まで逃げない
I won’t run.
（戸崎優(とさきゆう)）
があっ… ぐっ…
（ダグラス･アルメイダ）
オグラ･イクヤは どこだ？
Where is Ogura Ikuya?
教えてやれ マイヤーズ
Tell him, Myers.
（戸崎）
飼い犬は… 大変だな
It’s tough being a lapdog, isn’t it.
（注射器を刺す音）
永井(ながい)君！　何をやってるの？
Nagai-kun!
What are you doing?
Preparing to move the hideout!
（永井圭(ながいけい)）
アジトを移す準備ですよ
（泉）
私たちが
佐藤(さとう)に勝つチャンスは たった一度
We only have one chance to beat Satou.
大臣を襲う佐藤を
迎え撃つしかない
We have to ambush him when he
attacks the minister.
But...
でも それが いつなのかを
知ってるのは戸崎さんだけ
...the only one who knows when that
will happen is Tosaki-san!
（圭）
予定変更です
Change of plan.
We’re going to rescue Tosaki-san.
（圭）
これから戸崎さん救出に向かう
Intruders!
（警備１）
侵入者だ！
（圭）
戸崎さんが心配なのは
分かりますが―
I know you’re worried about Tosaki-san,
くれぐれも冷静にお願いしますよ
but please try to stay calm.
I know that.
分かってる
Tosaki-san!
（泉）
戸崎さん！
逃がすか！
I won’t let you escape!
（アルメイダ）
くそっ！
罰はきっちり受けてもらうからな
You’ll pay for that later.
（圭）
まずいですよ 平沢さん
あいつらの行き先―
This is bad, Hirasawa-san.
They’re heading towards...
アメリカ大使館です
the American Embassy.
（平沢(ひらさわ)）
大使館は完全な治外法権だ
The embassy is extraterritorial.
Neither the police nor the army
（平沢）
警察だろうが自衛隊だろうが
誰も手出し出来ないんだよ
can lay a hand on them there.
（圭）
もし逃げ込まれたら
そこで終わりってことだ
If they make it there,
that’s the end!
（佐藤(さとう)）
ふぅ
（佐藤）
さて 今日も派手にいきますか
Well then,
shall we give them a show?
New Opening Song Subs will be added next week!!
♪目を醒せ　このdestiny♪
♪逃れられないのなら♪
♪正しさも過ちも
全てを飲み込み闘う♪
♪騒(ざわ)めく　心の闇を
司(つかさど)る脅威♪
♪理性を　失くしかけてる
人間の真理♪
♪僕は知る　その無意味さを♪
♪偽りの平穏さえ　砕け散るなら♪
♪抗(あらが)う影　落とす♪
♪It's the end of escape
立ち上がる♪
♪その道しかないから♪
♪辿り着け　僕が目指した
小さなその希望に♪
♪差し伸べた　その手から♪
♪零れ落ちた弱さは♪
♪正しさも過ちも
全てを飲み込み狂った♪
Kuro-chan, , just once
more, please!
At the fastest, we can make it to the
embassy in about 10 minutes.
大使館まで早くて約10分
このままでは追い付けないぞ
We won’t be able to catch them.
Only if they can continue to use
（圭）
普通の道を通ればの話ですよ
the regular roads.
Go get them!
行ってこい
（圭ＩＢＭ）
アメリカに けんかを売るのは―
However you think about it, picking a
fight with America isn’t rational.
どう考えても
合理的じゃないですよ
Where are they?
やつらの車は？
At this point...
（カーリー･マイヤーズ）
今のところは
あっ！
STOP
Alright!
（圭）
よし 予想どおりの道に入った
They’ve taken the road we expected.
つかまってろ
Let’s catch up.
うっ
下村さん 聞こえますか
Shimomura-san!
Can you hear me?
I hear you.
聞こえてる！　今どこ？
Where are they?
The side street by the park ahead.
（インカム音声:圭）
その先に見える公園の脇道です！
STOP
（タイヤのすれる音）
（マイヤーズ）
うっ！
Back up!
引き返せ！
（マイヤーズ）
あっ しまった！
Oh no!
（衝突音）
（アルメイダ）
うっ うう…
なっ… 何を…
What are you-?
（銃声）
Reset.
リセットだ くそっ！
Shit.
ここまで来て…
We made it this far...
ぐっ… はぁっ
こいつを運ぶ　モタモタするな！
Help me carry him!
Hurry up!
（圭）
戸崎さんは！
Where’s Tosaki-san?
They escaped!
逃げられた　でもまだ近くに！
But...
they’re still close.
（圭）なっ くっ… 中野(なかの)！
Nakano!
（中野攻(なかのこう)）
おう！
Yeah!
Security will be strong near the embassy.
（圭）
大使館近くは警備が厳重です
平沢さんは事故の後始末を！
Hirasawa-san,
you clean up here!
（アルメイダ）
こっちだ 早くしろ！
This way.
Hurry up!
放せ…
Let me go.
黙れ
Shut up!
（注射器を刺す音）
（タブレットが落ちる音）
Where did they...?
（泉）
どこに…
実弾は少ないし 麻酔銃は残り１発
絶対に外せない
I only have a few real bullets,
and one tranquilizer dart left.
I can’t afford to miss.
あっ！
Don’t let your guard down.
（圭）
気を抜くな　向こうは亜人がいる！
They have an Ajin on their side.
（攻）
分かってるよ！
I know!
Tosaki-san!
（攻）
トザキさーん！　どこだーっ！
Where are you?
（圭）
大声出すな！　警備に見つかる！
（攻）
分かってるって！
Let’s go.
行くぞ
If we can get past here,
この裏を抜ければ 大使館はすぐだ
the embassy is close.
（アルメイダ）
あっ！
くっ… 何としても無力化しろ！
Do something, just take her out!
はい
Understood.
（マイヤーズ）
無駄な事を
What a waste.
（泉）
ああっ ううっ ぐっ…
I’ve smashed your knees.
（マイヤーズ）
ひざを潰した
You can’t escape,
逃げることも 死ぬことも出来ない
or die.
I hate women like you.
あんたみたいな女は大嫌いよ
You picked this fight.
しょせんは飼われてるだけなのに
馬鹿じゃない？
Are you stupid?
もうＩＢＭも出せないくせに
Even though you can’t send
out any more IBMs...
You could have escaped.
素直に逃げ出しとけば―
無駄に苦しむ必要もなかったのに…
You didn’t need to go through
all this pain.
Did you think I wouldn’t realize?
気付かれないとでも思った？
どこまでも哀れね ハハハッ…
How pitiful are you?
（踏み付けられる音）
（泉）ああっ…
私は… 決めたの…
I...
...made up my mind.
もう… 逃げないって！
Not to run...
...any more!
なっ ＩＢＭの濃度が！
The IBM concentration is...
（泉）
クロちゃん
もう一度だけ お願い！
Kuro-chan, just once more,
please!
うおおーっ！
This contract is between me and you alone.
（戸崎）
これは 私個人と君だけの契約だ
Obey my orders.
（アルメイダ）
私の命令に従え
これは…
These are...
相手の記憶が！？
...her memories!
はっ！
ちっ… どこまで使えない女だ！
How useless are you?
撃つなら撃て
If you’re gonna shoot, just do it!
I don’t need an Ajin that’s of
no use to me.
役立たずの亜人に用はない
It really would have been best
やはり実験動物は
おりに閉じ込めておくのが一番だな
to keep you locked up for experiments!
（発射音）
（アルメイダ）うっ…
な… 何を？
What-  How could-?
あなたは今すぐ 黙るべきだ
You should learn when
to shut your mouth!
Make no mistake.
勘違いしないで
I’m just
私は ただ 自分の仕事をしただけ
doing my job.
（攻）
トザキさーん
Tosaki-san!
Nagai!
おっ 永井！　こっちこっち！
This way!
もう あなたを倒す手立てはない
I have no other way to defeat you.
でも 私の仕事は完遂した
But my work here is done.
ホント あんたみたいな女は
大っ嫌いよ
I really...
...hate women like you.
はっ…
（銃声）
（マイヤーズ）
勘違いしないで
Make no mistake.
私は ただ
新しい人生を始めるだけ
I’m just
starting a new life.
フッ
Izumi-san!
（攻）
泉さーん！
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
Tosaki-san.
（泉）
戸崎さん！　戸崎さん！
Tosaki-san!
はっ！
こ… ここは？
Where are we?
アジトに戻る途中です
On our way back to the hideout.
Hirasawa-san and the others
後始末は 平沢さんたちがしてます
are taking care of the clean-up.
You should thank Izumi-san.
泉さんに
お礼言ったほうがいいっすよ
じゃなきゃ 今頃 どうなってたか
If not for her,
who knows where you’d be now.
What?
何？
はっ！
大臣は！
大臣のスケジュールはどうだった？
The minister-
What about the minister’s schedule?
Eh?
（攻）
え それって トザキさんしか
知らないんじゃ……
I thought you were the only one
who knew about that.
What did you say?
何だと？
あっ はぁ…
そういうことか
So that’s how it was.
Uhh..
（攻）
は？　どういうこと？
What are you talking about?
When is it?
いつなんだ？
まさか 今日なのか？
You mean-
Was it today?!
What were you thinking?
何を考えている！
Why didn’t you tell Nagai?
なぜ 永井に言わなかった！？
計画が台無しだ！
All our plans have gone to waste!
I’m sorry.
すいません
Everything we did was for today.
全て この日のためだ！
それなのに… それなのに君は！
And despite that-
Despite that, you-!
（攻）
え？
Eh?
済んだ事を怒っても
時間の無駄ですよ
It’s not worth worrying about
what’s over and done.
（圭）それより 今 出来る事を…
（戸崎）携帯は！？
It’s more important to think about what’s nex-
What about my phone?
私の携帯はどこだ！
Where’s my phone?
We picked it up for you.
こっちで回収しておきました
頼む… 出てくれ！
Come on.
Pick up.
Yes,
（曽我部(そかべ)）
はい 曽我部です
It’s Sokabe.
（大臣）
なぜだ！
どうして情報が漏れた！？
Why?
How did the information leak?
（ＳＰ１）
こ こちらへ！
This way!
（内閣次官）
なんで こんな目に…
How did things get like this?
（大臣）
あんたも
楽して大金を手にしたくせに―
I thought you guys were prepared
for this sort of thing.
今更 何を言う
Too late for you to complain.
（ＳＰ１）
やつは！？
This way is clear.
（ＳＰ２）
こちらにはいません
（ＳＰ１）
大臣！　急ぎましょう
Minister. Let’s hurry.
（銃声）
（ＳＰ３）
後ろへ！　ああっ…
Behind me!
（佐藤）
いやぁ 死んだふりってのは―
Ha, playing dead
なかなか楽しいもんだね
is pretty fun.
（田中(たなか)）
おっと　動くと頭が無くなるぞ
Watch out.
If you move, you lose your head.
あぁ…
あっ 見事なものだな
Congratulations.
I didn’t think
まさか ここまでやるとは
you would make it this far.
Wow, what an honor.
ハハ 光栄だね
まさか 大臣に褒められるなんて
To be praised by the minister himself.
貴様らの要求は 実験の公表と―
Your demands were
a public announcement of the experiments
and a recognition of rights for Ajin, correct.
亜人の権利を
認めさせることだったな
（佐藤）
だったら？
And if they were?
私が力になろう
I can help you!
I work as a government minister.
I can't guarantee anything,
曲がりなりにも
政府の大臣を務める身だ
but I'll make a proposal to the prime minister.
総理に進言してやる！
The prime minister?
つまり 我々の要求を認めると？
So he’ll recognize our demands?
ああ　私なら
彼らの罪を暴くことも出来る
Yes!
If you have me,
I can expose their crimes!
ゆくゆくは 亜人の自治区を
作ることだって夢ではない
Isn’t your end goal
to create a country ruled by ajin?
さ 佐藤さん
Sa-
Satou-san!
You’re a better politician than I expected.
思ったよりも
立派な政治家のようだ
（大臣）
ハハッ
ハハッ…
分かってくれれば それで…
Alright, if you agree, then-
（銃声）
（大臣）ううっ
（佐藤）
ありがとう
すばらしい演説だったよ
Thank you.
That was a wonderful performance.
Satou-san.
佐藤さん…
な… なんで…
Why...?
Hm?
ん？　何が？
What?
いや せっかく 俺らの要求が…
I mean,
he said they’d recognize our demands...
（佐藤）
田中くんも甘いなぁ
Tanaka-kun, don't be so naive.
政治家ってのは
うそをつくのが仕事だよ？
Politicians.
Lying is their job.
あ… でも…
B- but!
（ドアの開閉音）
（内閣次官）
ひいっ！　助けて 助けて…
S-spare us!
（携帯の着信音）
はい 曽我部です
Yes.
Yes, it’s Sokabe.
な なんだよ 辛気くさいなぁ…
Come on, you’re all so gloomy!
トザキさんも戻ったし
まだ佐藤を止めるチャンスは…
We got Tosaki-san back,
and our chance to stop Satou is still-
Zero.
ゼロだ
The only lead we had was the minister.
Now he’s dead.
我々が行動を読める大臣は死んだ
もう打つ手はない
There’s nothing more to be done.
でも…
But!
文句なら彼女に言え
If you have complaints, tell them to her.
あぁ…
ふぅ…
We’ve finished.
（平沢）
終わりました
Huh?
（攻）
ん？　終わったって 何が？
Wait.
What’s finished?
Cleaning up tonight's mess.
現場の後始末だ
放っておくと 騒ぎになるからな
If we had left it,
it would have caused a stir.
悪いな 給料以上の仕事まで…
Sorry about that.
You shouldn't have to do something your salary doesn't cover.
（平沢）
そいつは構いませんが
亜人だという女の行方が…
We don’t care about that,
but we don’t know where the other
Ajin has gone.
（泉）
あの人なら 大丈夫です
Since it’s her,
you don’t have to worry.
きっと
もう誰にも見つからないと…
I’m sure no one will find her.
フン 亜人だからって
かばうつもりか？
Are you covering for her because
she’s an Ajin?
そういうわけでは…
That’s not why- !
If you do that again,
（戸崎）
今度 同じようなまねをしてみろ
I’ll send you to the dissection table.
実験部屋送りにするからな
トザキさん！　いくらなんでも！
Tosaki-san!
How could you?!
それより 永井のやつは？
姿が見えませんが
More importantly, what about Nagai?
I haven’t seen him around.
あいつも後処理だ
He’s also doing clean-up.
Using the laptop we got from
the Americans’ car,
連中の車から回収した
ラップトップで―
国防総省に偽のメールを送っている
he’s sending an email to the
Department of Defense.
（戸崎）
オグラ博士の件も
セーフハウスの襲撃も―
The incidents with Professor Ogura,
and at the safe house...
全て佐藤の仕業と報告するそうだ
he’s reporting Satou as the
culprit of all of those attacks.
Are you saying that Satou kidnapped me?
（オグラ･イクヤ）
佐藤が
俺を拉致したことにするのか？
そうすれば アメリカも
佐藤を狙うでしょうからね
If I do that,
maybe the Americans will go after Satou.
They might stop him for us.
僕らの代わりに
止めてくれるかもしれない
ついでに あの２人には―
And while you’re at it,
you’ll have those two Americans
go missing, with that email
そのメールを最後に
行方不明になってもらう… か
as their last trace.
You’re very crafty.
随分と悪知恵が働くもんだなぁ
褒め言葉と取っておきますよ
I’ll take that as a compliment.
ん？　そのｈａｓは要らんな
You don’t need that word.
What?
え？　でも…
But...
It doesn’t sound native,
現地じゃ表現しないってだけで
文法的には合ってる
but it’s grammatically correct.
試験なら満点だ
If this were a test,
you’d get full marks.
Of course I would.
でしょうね
（オグラ）
だが 試験も受けさせて
もらえなければ意味がない
But,
if they don’t let you take the test,
that means nothing.
What do you plan to do?
これから どうするつもりだ？
まだ何か方法があるはずですよ
There must still be a way.
想定外の邪魔が入っただけで―
To have all our plans fail just because
of unexpected obstacles...
作戦が失敗した訳じゃ…
ん？
[screen- New video uploaded]
朝には ここを引き払う
First we need to get out of here.
もう準備も出来てるようだしな
It seems like
we’re already prepared for that.
引き払うって どこに？
Get out, to... where?
知るか　自分で考えろ
No idea.
You come up with something.
What do you mean?
You're supposed to be in charge.
何だよ 無責任だな！
大臣が死んだ今―
The minister is dead,
私も じきに委員会を除名される
and the Committee is about to fire me.
行く当てがないのは同じだ
We also have no place to go.
It seems like
（圭）
まだ希望はあるみたいですよ
there’s still hope.
（攻）
ああ？
A new video from Satou was uploaded.
佐藤から新しい犯行予告が
アップされました
（モニター音声:佐藤）
見てくれたかい？
Did you see?
今 死体になったのは
厚労省の大臣だ
Just now, we killed the Minister of
Health, Labour, and Welfare.
Although it probably hasn’t made the news.
まだ ニュースに
なってないだろうがね
We have one target remaining.
残るターゲットは１人
President Hashiguchi of Musashi Heavy Industries.
武蔵(むさし)重工の橋口(はしぐち)会長だ
取締役会が開かれる
３日後の19時―
At the Board of Directors meeting
in three days, at 7 p.m.,
I’m going to kill him.
殺しにいくよ
（一同）
なっ…
He’s giving a date and
time for the attack?
犯行日時の指定だと？
Satou-san might like to fight,
but what he really likes is playing games.
どこまでも戦いたがりで
遊び好きなんですよ 佐藤さんは
（モニター音声:佐藤）
これは宣戦布告だ
This is a declaration of war.
会長が姿を現さない場合は―
If the president doesn't show his face,
we'll take that as evidence that he was
亜人に対する“非人道的な研究”を
認めたと見なす
complicit in the inhumane experiments
that were performed on Ajin.
そして どこに隠れようが
必ず殺す
Then,
no matter how he tries to hide,
we'll find him and kill him.
（ゲン）
じょ 冗談だろ
Is this a joke?
こんなことしたら
警備が厳重になるだけだって
All this will do is increase security!
（高橋(たかはし)）
奥山(おくやま)は何も言わなかったのかよ！
Okuyama,
didn't he tell you anything?
Coming up with the strategy isn’t my job.
（奥山(おくやま)）
作戦を立てるのは僕の役目じゃない
だから口出しもしない
So he doesn’t tell me about that.
（高橋）
ちっ 田中さん！　あんたは…
Tanaka-san!
You-!
（高橋）あっ…
（ゲン）あっ…
何か問題でも？
Is there some kind of problem?
（高橋）
え いや…
N- no.
Satou-san.
佐藤さん なぜ
こっちが不利になるようなまねを？
Why...
What's the point of lying to them like this?
（佐藤）
不利じゃないよ
むしろ 有利だと思ったほうがいい
It's not a lie.
This is part of our plan.
は？
This way,
we’ll bet able to use our secret weapon.
この状況だからこそ
秘密兵器が生かせるんじゃないか
（テレビ音声:キャスター）
こちら記者会見場です
We are reporting live from the scene.
Right now,
現在 亜人 佐藤の
犯行予告を受けた―
a joint press conference is being held
by the government and Musashi Heavy Industries
武蔵重工と政府による
合同会見が行われています
in response to Satou's recent threats.
No matter what happens,
（テレビ音声:橋口(はしぐち)）
私は何があっても
テロリストには屈しません
I refuse to give in to terrorists.
よって いかなる脅しがあろうと
逃げも隠れもしない
Therefore,
whatever threats they make,
I won’t run or hide.
You mean you plan to-
-dangerous-
（報道陣１）
取締役会は開くんですね！
（報道陣２）
あまりに無謀ではありませんか！
That’s quite a-
-will you do about-
（報道陣３）
具体的な警備体制は！
What are your plans for security?
Will you be okay?
もちろん 我々も
万全の警備で望む所存であり―
Of course, we also desire the utmost security
and we have already requested cooperation
from the government.
既に政府への協力も
要請してあります
以上でございます
That is all.
（司会）
次に官房長官からの説明となります
You mean-
Wait a minute, that’s-
Next, a briefing from the Chief Cabinet Secretary.
I am Chief Cabinet Secretary Mitsui.
（三井(みつい)）
官房長官の三井です
度重なるテロ行為に対し―
In response to the increasing threat of ajin terrorists,
the Cabinet has met and decided as a result to enact a new law.
政府内で閣議決定された
亜人に対する特別措置法が―
本会議で成立しました
そして今回の法案により―
Under these new measures,
all involved government ministries have cooperated,
各省庁と連携をとり
新たな防衛部隊を組織しました
and a new defensive force has been formed.
They will be called...
その名称は―
対亜人特選群です
The Anti-Ajin Special Force.
な 対亜だと！？
The Anti-A-
(translator’s note: ‘tai’ means ‘anti-‘)
タイヤ？　何それ？
Tire?
What’s that?
An elite squad specializing in fighting Ajin.
対亜人に特化した精鋭部隊だ
自衛隊の第一空挺(くうてい)団や―
It’s made up of members selected from
ＳＡＴから選抜した連中で
構成されている
the SAT and the Self-Defense Force
1st Airborne Brigade.
新たに組織された部隊にしては
詳しいですね
You’re awfully well-informed about such a newly formed organization.
はっ！　ああ―
Ah. So that’s how it is.
そういうことか
Huh?
は？　何？　どういうこと？
What?
What do you mean?
There’s no way
特殊部隊が
２日足らずで用意出来るわけがない
they can put together such a force
in less than two days.
つまり 既に組織されていながら
正式な活動が出来なかった
Which means...
it had already been formed,
it just couldn’t act officially.
Isn’t that right?
そうですね？
Yes.
ああ
Up until now,
it had been illegal for such a force to exist.
これまでは
その存在自体が違法だったからな
でも 今回の法案を機に
発足させたことにすれば―
But,
because of this law,
その存在は合法になる… か
their existence becomes legal.
That’s quite a big deal.
大したものですね
建前を考えることにかけては―
After all,
this country is the best in the world
世界で 一番うまいからな
この国は
at putting its public image first.
（攻）
で？
強(つえ)ぇの そのタイヤってのは？
And?
Are they strong?
The Anti-As.
対亜が使用する装備は―
The equipment used by the Anti-Ajin Forces
全て武蔵重工が供出した
非人道的な最新兵器だ
was all produced by Musashi Heavy Industries.
It’s a new, inhumane weapon.
It will be used by
それを
現在の日本で考えられうる―
what is now Japan’s strongest force.
最強の部隊が使用する
もはや 我々の出番はないのかもな
Soon...
they might not need us.
確かに
そのほうがありがたいですね
That’s true.
I hope it turns out that way.
誰かが佐藤さんを止めてくれるなら
それが何よりです
As long as someone stops Satou,
that’s the most important thing.
本当にそう思うのか？
Do you really think that?
Of course not.
なわけないでしょう
今更 指をくわえて見ている気は
毛頭ありません
Do you think I could just sit back and
do nothing after all we’ve done?
何のために あんたと手を組んだと
思ってるんです？
Why do you think
I joined forces with you?
ああ そのとおりだ
Yes.
That’s exactly right.
これが最後のチャンスです
This is our last chance.
何があっても 佐藤さんを止める！
No matter what,
we have to stop Satou!
To be continued...
Mou akitakara koukan shiyou
Since I'm tired of it, let's exchange it
♪もう飽きたから交換しよう♪
Omae ga motteru futsuu no to
With the normal one that you are holding
♪お前が持ってる普通のと♪
Kira kira shiteru kami no kaado to
A shining paper card and
♪キラキラしてる神のカードと♪
Zara zara shiteru kami no kaado
A rough paper card
♪ザラザラしてる紙のカード♪
Kondo uchi ni kitara
Next time you come to my house
♪今度家に来たら♪
Zenbu miseteyaru yo dakara
I'll show you everything, so...
♪全部見せてやるよ♪
♪だから♪
Koutei no sumi ni futari, kaze ga fuite ima
At the edge of the schoolyard the wind blows...
♪校庭の隅に二人 風が吹いて♪
♪今なら言えるかな♪
nara ieru ka na?
can I say it now?
Dare nimo iwanai kotoba
Words never spoken to another person
♪誰にも言わない言葉♪
Yasashiku suru kara asobi ni kite yo
I'll be gentle so come and play often
♪「優しくするから
遊びに来てよ」♪
Nandemo ageru yo, ne
I'll give you anything, hey
♪「何でもあげるよ ねぇ」♪
Korekara zutto tomodachi de ite yo
Let's be friends forever
♪「これからずっと
友達でいてよ」♪
Preview
Things are getting kind of
tough in this country.